When Make Believe Is Just Not Enough!
Faces of Death II is a documentary, horror film directed by John Alan Schwartz.
Brief scenes of death related material: mortuaries, accidents and
police work are filmed by TV crews and home video cameras.
Some of it is most likely fake, some not as much.
Dr. Francis B. Gröss, played by Michael Carr.
Self (archive footage), played by John Hinckley Jr..
Faces of Death (later re-released as The Original Faces of Death) is a 1978 American mondo horror film written and
directed by John Alan Schwartz, credited under the pseudonyms "Conan Le Cilaire" and "Alan Black" respectively.
The film, presented as if it were an actual
documentary, centers on pathologist Francis B.
Gröss, played by actor Michael Carr, who presents the viewer with footage
showing different gruesome ways of dying from a variety of sources.
Many scenes were faked for the film, but most portions include
pre-existing video footage of real deaths and its aftermath.
Faces of Death received generally negative reviews, but it was a huge success at
the box office, reportedly grossing over $35 million worldwide.
It gained a cult following and spawned several sequels, the first
of which, Faces of Death II, was released in 1981.
The film explores themes of necrophilia, gore, car
accident, fake documentary, mortuary.
The tone is dark.